<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>RDO</title>
  <subtitle>Tag: Mitaka</subtitle>
  <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/</id>
  <link href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/"/>
  <link href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/tag/mitaka.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-06-08T17:52:06+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name/>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>What did you do in Mitaka? David Moreau Simard</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/05/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-david-moreau-simard/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/05/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-david-moreau-simard/</id>
    <published>2016-05-06T15:47:48+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing our series "What Did You Do In Mitaka?", I spoke with David Moreau Simard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/zqt2x-5f14b4?from=yiiadmin" data-link="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/zqt2x-5f14b4?from=yiiadmin" height="100" width="100%" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" data-name="pb-iframe-player"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(If the above player doesn't work for you, please download the recording &lt;a href="https://rdocommunity.podbean.com/mf/play/qp7cm4/david-simard.mp3"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm speaking with &lt;a href="https://github.com/dmsimard"&gt;David Moreau Simard&lt;/a&gt;, who is one of the engineers
who works on &lt;a href="//rdoproject.org"&gt;RDO&lt;/a&gt; at Red Hat. Thanks for taking time to speak with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DMSimard&lt;/strong&gt;: It's a pleasure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: What did you work on in Mitaka?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm part of the RDO engineering team at Red Hat.
My role is mostly around continuous integration and making sure that
RDO works.
This means that some days I could be implementing new ways of testing
RDO or some other days fixing bugs identified by our CI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as Mitaka is concerned, we got Packstack to a point where it's
able to install and run Tempest against itself.
This is awesome because it's a great way to make sure everything works
properly, sort of a sanity check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This improvement allowed us to make Packstack gate against itself
upstream to prevent regressions from merging by testing each commit.
This was part of a plan to make Packstack part of our testing
pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mitaka, we started using a new project called &lt;a href="https://dmsimard.com/2015/12/07/thinking-outside-the-box-and-outside-the-gate-to-improve-openstack-and-rdo/"&gt;WeIRDO&lt;/a&gt;.
It's meant to use upstream gate integration tests inside our own RDO
testing pipeline.
We really improved our testing coverage in Mitaka with TripleO
quickstart and WeIRDO.
With WeIRDO, we're able to easily test RDO trunk packages against
Packstack and Puppet-OpenStack and the jobs that they provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built a great relationship with projects that consume RDO packages
throughout development cycles.
We mutually benefit from essentially testing each other. So it makes a
lot of sense to stay in touch with these guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I can really tell how the testing coverage for RDO has
improved tremendously, even since liberty.
Mitaka is really the best and most tested release of RDO yet. I want
to extend my thanks to everyone that was involved in making it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: So how about in Newton? What do you think is coming in Newton for
you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;: So, Mitaka was already an awesome cycle from the perspective of
testing coverage that we had for RDO.
We want to keep working on that foundation to increase the coverage
further.
I also want to spend some time on improving monitoring and automation
to make troubleshooting problems easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trunk breaks all the time, and so it takes a lot of time to
troublshoot that, and we want to make that easier. But also have
visibility into the problems that could be coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier I talked about WeIRDO and how we use upstream gate jobs in our
testing pipeline.
In Newton, we want to add Kolla back into our testing pipeline through
WeIRDO.
I had some issues getting Kolla to work reliably in Mitaka but they've
fixed some problems upstream since then so we'll take another look at
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just recently, there's also the Chef OpenStack community – they've been working on
integration testing their cookbooks in the gate.
I'm definitely interested in seeing what they have, and possibly leveraging their work once they're ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other large chunk of work will probably come from our effort in
streamlining and centralizing the different components of RDO.
Right now, we're a bit all over the place… But we've already started
working towards moving to a software factory instance.
Software factory is a project to provide upstream's testing ecosystem
with Git, Zuul, Nodepool, Gerrit and Jenkins.. but in a box, an
appliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will definitely make things easier for everyone since everything
from RDO will be expected to be in this one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you very much for your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;: I appreciate yours, and it was great working on this great release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;David is dmsimard on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/dmsimard"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href="https://github.com/dmsimard"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, and on IRC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What did you do in Mitaka: Emilien Macchi</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/05/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-emilien-macchi/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/05/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-emilien-macchi/</id>
    <published>2016-05-04T21:03:33+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing my series of interviews with RDO engineers, here's my chat with Emilien Macchi, who I talked with at OpenStack Summit last week in Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to talk about what you did in Mitaka, please contact me at &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#114;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#119;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#104;&amp;#097;&amp;#116;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;"&gt;&amp;#114;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#119;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#104;&amp;#097;&amp;#116;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/fzkg3-5f06ba?from=yiiadmin" data-link="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/fzkg3-5f06ba?from=yiiadmin" height="100" width="100%" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" data-name="pb-iframe-player"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If the above player doesn't work for you, please download the audio &lt;a href="https://rdocommunity.podbean.com/mf/play/uinm26/emilien_macchi.mp3"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm speaking with Emilien Macchi, who is one of the people that
worked on the Mitaka release of OpenStack. Thank you for taking time
to speak with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emilien&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you for welcoming me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: What did you do in Mitaka?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;: In Mitaka, most of my tasks were related to packaging testing. I'm
currently leading the Puppet OpenStack group, which is a team where we
develop some Puppet modules that deploy OpenStack in production. Red
Hat is using the Puppet modules in TripleO, so we can automate the
deployment of OpenStack services. Recently we switched the gates of
OpenStack Infra to use RDO packaging. We had a lot of issued before
because we didn't have much CI. But since Mitaka, the RDO and the
Puppet teams worked a lot together to make sure that we can provide
some testing together. We can fix things very early when it's broken
upstream. Like when we have a new dependency or when we have a change
in the requirements. That was this kind of test where you provide very
early feedback to the RDO people that are doing the packaging. It was
very interesting to work with RDO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provided early feedback on the builds, on the failures. We also
contributed to … I say "we", I don't like to say "I" … we, my
group, my Puppet group, we contributed to the new packages that we
have in Mitaka. We updated the spec in the package so we could have
more features, and more services in the RDO projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing! Testing every day. Testing, testing, testing. Participating
in the events that the RDO community is having, like the weekly
meetings, the testing days. It was very interesting for us to have
this relationship with the RDO team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I'm looking forward to Newton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: What do you anticipate you'll be working on in Newton?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;: Well, that's an interesting question. We are talking about this
week. [At OpenStack Summit, Austin.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge for us … the biggest challenge, I guess, is to follow
the release velocity of upstream projects. We have a bunch of projects
in OpenStack, and it's very hard to catch up with all of the projects
at the same time. In the meantime we have to because those projects,
they are in the RDO project and also in the products, so that's
something we need to … we need to scale the way that we producing
all this work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something we are very focused on right now is to use the Software
Factory project, which is how OpenStack Infra is operating to build
OpenStack software. This is a project - an open source project - which
is now used by RDO. We can have this same way as upstream, but for
downstream - we can have the same way to produce the RDO artifacts,
like the packages and the Puppet modules, and so on. That's the next
big challenge, is to be fully integrated with Software Factory, to
implement the missing features we will need to make the testing
better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, that's the biggest challenge: Improve the testing, and stopping
doing manual things, automate all the things, that is the next
challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you very much. Thanks for your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you for your time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What did you do in Mitaka? Javier Peña</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-javier-pena/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-javier-pena/</id>
    <published>2016-04-26T17:18:06+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We're continuing our series of "What did you do in Mitaka?"
interviews. This one is with Javier Peña.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/82a4c-5ec74f?from=yiiadmin" data-link="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/82a4c-5ec74f?from=yiiadmin" height="100" width="100%" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" data-name="pb-iframe-player"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If the above player doesn't work for you, you can download the file &lt;a href="https://rdocommunity.podbean.com/mf/play/fgk3cc/javier-pena-mitaka.mp3"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich&lt;/strong&gt;: Today I'm speaking with Javier Peña, who is another member
of the Red Hat OpenStack engineering team. Thanks for making time to
speak with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Javier&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you very much for inviting me, Rich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: What did you work on in the Mitaka cycle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;J&lt;/strong&gt;: I've been focusing on three main topics. First one was keeping the
DLRN infrastructure up and running. As you know, this is the service
we use to create RPM packages for our RDO distribution, straight from
the upstream master commits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's been evolving quite a lot during this cycle. We ended up with so
much success that we're having infrastructure issues. One of the
topics for the next cycle will be to improve the infrastructure, but
that's something we'll talk about later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These packages have now been consumed by the TripleO, Kolla, and
Puppet OpenStack CI, so we're quite well tested. Not only are we
testing them directly from the RDO trunk repositories, but we have
external trials as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that I have also been working on packaging, just like some
other colleagues on the team who've you've already had a chance to
talk to - Haikel, Chandan - I have been contributing packages both to
upstream Fedora, and also RDO directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, I'm also one of the core maintainers of Packstack. In
this cycle we've been adding support for some services such as AODH
and Gnocchi. Also we switched Mysql support from the Python side. We
switched libraries, and we had to do some work with the upstream
Puppet community to make sure that PyMysql, which is now the default
Python library used upstream, is also used inside the Puppet core and
we can use it in Packstack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: You mentioned briefly infrastructure changes that you'll be making
in the upcoming cycle. Can you tell us more about what you have
planned for Newton?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;J&lt;/strong&gt;: Right now the DLRN infrastructure is building 6 different lines of
repositories. We have CentOS master, which is now Newton. Mitaka,
Liberty, and Kilo. And we have two branches for Fedora as well. So
this is quite a heavy load for VMs that we're running right now. We
were having some issues in the cloud we were running that instance. So
what we're doing now is we are migrating to the CentOS CI
infrastructure. We are having a much bigger machine in there. And also
what we are going to do is we will be publishing the resulting
repositories using the CentOS CDN, which is way more reliable than
what we could build with individual VMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you again for your time. And we look forward to seeing what
comes in Newton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;J&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you very much, Rich.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What did you do in MItaka? Haïkel Guémar</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-haikel-guemar/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-haikel-guemar/</id>
    <published>2016-04-22T14:51:28+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this installment of the "What Did You Do in Mitaka" series, I'm
speaking with Haïkel Guémar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe id="audio_iframe" src="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/z8zks-5ea7c6?from=yiiadmin" data-link="http://www.podbean.com/media/player/z8zks-5ea7c6?from=yiiadmin" height="100" width="100%" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" data-name="pb-iframe-player"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If the above player doesn't work for you, you can download the audio &lt;a href="https://rdocommunity.podbean.com/mf/play/pfcayj/haikel-guemar-mitaka.mp/"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich&lt;/strong&gt;: Thanks for making time to speak with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Haïkel&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: So, tell me, what did you do in Mitaka?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;: I work on the &lt;a href="http://rdoproject.org"&gt;RDO&lt;/a&gt; engineering team - the team that is responsible
for the stewardship of RDO. For this cycle, I've been focusing on our
new packaging work flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were using, for a long time, a piece of infrastructure taken from
Fedora, CentOS, and GitHub. This didn't work very well, and was not
providing a consistent experience for the contributors. So we've been
working with another team at Red Hat to provide a more integrated
platform, and one that mirrors the one that we have upstream, based on
the same tools - meaning Git, Gerrit, Jenkins, Nodepool, Zuul - that is
called &lt;a href="https://github.com/redhat-cip/software-factory"&gt;Software Factory&lt;/a&gt;. So we've been working with the Software
Factory team to provide a specialization of that platform called
&lt;a href="https://github.com/redhat-cip/rpmfactory"&gt;RPMFactory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RPMFactory is a platform specialized for producing RPMs in a
continuous delivery fashion. It has all the advantages of the old
tooling we have been using, but with more consistency. You don't have
to look in different places to find the source code, the packaging,
and stuff like that. Everything is under a single portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's what I've been focusing on during this cycle, on top of my
usual duties, which is producing packages and fixing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: And looking forward to the Newton release, what do you think you're
going to be working on in that cycle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;: While we've been working in the new workflow, we've been setting a
new goal, that is to decrease the gap between upstream releases and
RDO releases down to 2 weeks. Well, we did it &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/rdo-mitaka-released/"&gt;on the very same day&lt;/a&gt; for
Mitaka! So my goal would be for Newton to do as good as this time, or
even better. Why not under 2 hours? Not putting on ourselves more
pressure, but to try to release almost at the same time as upstream
GA, RDO. And also with the same quality standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the few things that I was not happy with during the Mitaka
cycle was mostly the fact that we didn't manage to release some
packages in time, so I'd like to do better. Soon enough I will be
asking for people to fill in a wish list on packaging, so that we are
able to work on that earlier. And so we could release them on time
with GA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: Thanks again for taking the time to do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you Rich, for the series.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RDO Blogs, Week of April 18</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/rdo-blogs-week-of-april-18/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/rdo-blogs-week-of-april-18/</id>
    <published>2016-04-18T17:57:52+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This has been a big few weeks for RDO, and for OpenStack in general, with the Mitaka release coming out, and OpenStack Summit just around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's some of what RDO enthusiasts have been blogging about in the last few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RDO Mitaka released&lt;/strong&gt; by Rich Bowen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The RDO community is pleased to announce the general availability of the RDO build for OpenStack Mitaka for RPM-based distributions - CentOS Linux 7 and Red Hat Enterprise Linux. RDO is suitable for building private, public, and hybrid clouds and Mitaka is the 13th release from the OpenStack project, which is the work of more than 2500 contributors from around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… read more at &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/65"&gt;http://tm3.org/65&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What, Why, and How is the CentOS Cloud SIG?&lt;/strong&gt; by Rich Bowen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;2 years ago we started the CentOS Cloud SIG. Progress has been slow but steady. Slow, I think, because we've not done a wonderful job of explaining what it's for, and why it matters. But it has been a very important aspect of moving the RDO project forward, so it deserves better explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… read more at &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/66"&gt;http://tm3.org/66&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naming is hard or Who Let The Vowels Out&lt;/strong&gt; by Alan Pevec&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When Derek Higgins started the tool to build OpenStack packages based on latest upstream aka "trunk" changes, the name Delorean seemed like a good choice: the tool is keeping older builds so you could "go back in time" like with a time machine, it's geeky enough and there's Irish connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… read more at &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/67"&gt;http://tm3.org/67&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrating OpenStack into the Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt; by Michael Solberg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Adoption of OpenStack in the enterprise has been progressing steadily over the last two years. As a Forrester Report* on enterprise adoption from September noted, “OpenStack demonstrates the completeness, robustness, and capability upon which a broader range of adopters can depend.” OpenStack deployments have proven to be complex in larger IT organizations though, but not because of the reasons that you might anticipate. Much has been made about the complexity of installing the software, but we’ve found that the lion’s share of effort in these implementation comes around the practice of integrating IaaS into the fabric of enterprise IT and evolving existing processes to meet the expectations of the user community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… read more at &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/68"&gt;http://tm3.org/68&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting Started with Puppet for Keystone&lt;/strong&gt; by Adam Young&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tripleo uses Puppet to manage the resources in a deployment. Puppet has a command line tool to look at resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… read more at &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/69"&gt;http://tm3.org/69&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do in Mitaka: Ihar Hrachyshka talks about Neutron&lt;/strong&gt; by Rich Bowen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this installment of our "What did you do in Mitaka?" series, Ihar Hrachyshka talks about his work on Neutron both in Mitaka, and what's planned for Newton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… read (and listen) more at &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/6a"&gt;http://tm3.org/6a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What did you do in Mitaka? : Ivan Chavero&lt;/strong&gt; by Rich Bowen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The OpenStack cloud software project recently released the Mitaka release. RDO is a community distribution of OpenStack. I've invited several of the engineers that work on RDO to talk about what they did in the Mitaka cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… read (and listen) more at &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/6b"&gt;http://tm3.org/6b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning something new about Oslo Versioned Objects&lt;/strong&gt; byGorka Eguileor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you work on an OpenStack project that is in the process of adopting Versioned Objects or has recently adopted them, like we have in Cinder, you’ve probably done some code reviews, and even implemented a couple of Versioned Objects yourself, and are probably thinking that you know your way around them pretty well, but maybe there are some gaps in that knowledge that you are not aware of, specially if you are taking Nova’s or Cinder’s code as reference, at least I know I had some gaps. If you aren’t a seasoned Versioned Object user like the Nova people are, I recommend you keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… read more at &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/6c"&gt;http://tm3.org/6c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TripleO with already deployed servers&lt;/strong&gt; by James Slagle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been prototyping how to use TripleO with already deployed
and provisioned servers. In such a scenario, Nova and Ironic would not be used
to do the initial operating system provisioning of the Overcloud nodes.
Instead, the nodes would already be powered on, running an OS, and ready to
start to configure OpenStack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… read more at &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/6d"&gt;http://tm3.org/6d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What did you do in Mitaka:  Ihar Hrachyshka talks about Neutron</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-ihar-hrachyshka-talks-about-neutron/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-ihar-hrachyshka-talks-about-neutron/</id>
    <published>2016-04-15T18:08:04+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this installment of our "What did you do in Mitaka?" series, Ihar Hrachyshka talks about his work on Neutron both in Mitaka, and what's planned for Newton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can listen below. If the player doesn't work for you, you can listen &lt;a href="http://rdocommunity.podbean.com/mf/web/sipki2/ihar_hrachyshka_mitaka.mp3/"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe id="audio_iframe" src="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/7ximn-5e7230" width="100%" height="100" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich&lt;/strong&gt;: Hello, I'm speaking with &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/64"&gt;Ihar Hrachyshka&lt;/a&gt; about the work that he did
in the RDO community on the &lt;a href="http://releases.openstack.org/mitaka/index.html"&gt;Mitaka release of OpenStack&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you for
taking time to speak with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ihar&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you for having me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: Could you mention the things that you've worked on in Mitaka, both
upstream, and also specifically for &lt;a href="http://rdoproject.org"&gt;RDO&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;: One thing that I was focusing on during Mitaka in upstream is - we
are looking at how we can enhance the upgrade story for the project I
work on, which is &lt;a href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Neutron"&gt;Neutron&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(See &lt;a href="http://docs.openstack.org/releasenotes/neutron/mitaka.html"&gt;Neutron Mitaka release notes&lt;/a&gt;  )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of good work done in this regard on other projects, in
previous cycles, like in Nova. And Neutron was kind of lagging on
that. During Mitaka, we formed a sub-team that looks specifically into
the upgrade story, and we've identified several pain points that we
were addressing during this cycle, and plan to continue the work in
Neutron, and forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that we've identified is even though so-called rolling
upgrades were kind of supported in the sense that there was some code
to handle that scenario, for upgrades. But it was never actually
validated in our CI gate, so no-one could be sure that it actually
worked. So that was one thing that we tackled. We added proper jobs to
validate these scenarios, and make sure that they work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing for upgrades is that we are looking at reducing and
maybe even eliminating any downtime for API endpoints for Neutron,
especially in the case when you have highly-available controllers. That
involves a lot of work in the code base, a lot of change there to
refactor the code. We've already started the work during Mitaka, and
we're going to proceed with that in Newton. We hope that we complete
this work in Newton, and then for all upgrades starting from Newton to
the next release, operators will be able to retain their Neutron API
available while controllers are upgraded one by one. That's one thing
that I was working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other things. There was a lot of work done in Neutron in the
scope of Quality of Service (QOS). The initial support for QOS in
Neutron was merged in Liberty, but it's still quite limited, so we
expand on what we had done in that release. Specifically, the initial
support was just for OpenVSwitch, but in Mitaka we added support for
Linuxbridge ml2 driver. We also added role-based access control for QOS
policies. We added support for so-called DSCP tags, which is a feature
to prioritize traffic based on which port it came from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting thing that we finally tackled in Mitaka is MTU
support. This is one of the huge pain points that were identified
by operators in the past, that Neutron, while being the networking
solution for OpenStack, cannot actually properly handle MTUs - which
stands for Maximum Transfer Unit. Neutron could not actually handle,
neither standard MTUs for ethernet, nor so-called jumbo frames, which
is really bad. It means that instances did not have access to the full
capabilities of the underlying physical infrastructure. That should
hopefully go away in Mitaka, because there were several changes there,
both on the Neutron side, and on Nova, which now should make Neutron
work out of the box, both for non-standard and standard MTU sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, one thing to note, apart from pure upstream work in the
Master branch, is that in Neutron, in this Mitaka release, we adopted
a new approach to handle backports for stable branches. Now instead of
waiting for something to break in a user installation, and then
reacting to their bug reports, we are proactively backporting all of
the bug fixes from the latest master branch into stable branches, and
release new stable releases, often. We hope that it will reduce the
number of painful problems, in actual installations that rely on stable
branches, very significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: This sounds like an enormous amount of work. How many people are
you working with across how many organizations, would you estimate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;: In OpenStack it's always that you work with other people. I would
say … I don't know … there are I think 5, 6, major contributors to
Neutron. Surely, nothing comes in OpenStack if you're just single. So
that's collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you very much for your time, and we look forward to seeing
what comes in Newton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I: Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What did you do in Mitaka? : Ivan Chavero</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-ivan-chavero/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-ivan-chavero/</id>
    <published>2016-04-14T16:53:07+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first in what will hopefully be a long series of interviews with OpenStack engineers about what they worked on in the Mitaka cycle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://openstack.org/"&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt;  cloud software project recently released the &lt;a href="http://releases.openstack.org/mitaka/index.html"&gt;Mitaka
release&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;a href="http://rdoproject.org/"&gt;RDO&lt;/a&gt; is a community distribution of OpenStack. I've invited
several of the engineers that work on RDO to talk about what they did
in the Mitaka cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe id="audio_iframe" src="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/spvip-5e6b58" width="100%" height="100" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the above player doesn't appear, or doesn't work for you, you can listen &lt;a href="http://rdocommunity.podbean.com/mf/play/urpzjr/ivan_chavero_packstack.mp3"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich&lt;/strong&gt;: Mitaka is ready now, and before we move on to Newton, we should
celebrate what we've done in Mitaka. I'm speaking with &lt;a href="http://tm3.org/63"&gt;Ivan
Chavero&lt;/a&gt;. I
understand that you worked primarily on &lt;a href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Packstack"&gt;packstack&lt;/a&gt;. I've had to
correct a number of people over the last few months who think that
packstack is abandoned, and we're not doing it any more. While, at the
same time, the people at &lt;a href="www.cern.ch"&gt;CERN&lt;/a&gt; use packstack for a lot of things. and I
know that they're an unusual case, but there are other people that are
using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you did in the Mitaka cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ivan&lt;/strong&gt;: Well, we fixed a lot of bugs. We had a lot of problems because
there was some &lt;a href="http://docs.openstack.org/developer/keystone/http-api.html#should-i-use-v2-0-or-v3"&gt;migration from Keystone version 2 to Keystone version 3&lt;/a&gt;.
We added some other components like, &lt;a href="http://superuser.openstack.org/articles/ceilometer-gnocchi-and-aodh-liberty-progress"&gt;Ceilometer was split into aodh
and Gnocci&lt;/a&gt;, and we added that stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it's pretty stable right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We added more features to
Neutron. Everything we have to … the new stuff, we have to test. We
add it to Packstack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to add &lt;a href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Magnum"&gt;Magnum&lt;/a&gt;, but it wasn't a priority. And there's other
stuff like &lt;a href="http://ceph.com/"&gt;Ceph&lt;/a&gt; that we wanted to add, but it was just like, let's fix
bugs, let's fix the stuff we need, and keep Packstack stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did a lot of bug fixes for Packstack being able to work properly
with the CI infrastructure. Pretty much fixing a lot of bugs that we
found on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: Some of those other things that you mentioned - Magnum and Ceph and
so on, are those going to be goals for the Newton cycle, then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;: Well, I want them to be goals, but I have to discuss it with the
community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: Who else in the community is working on Packstack?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;: There's a lot of people. In this cycle we had a lot of
contributions from outside the RDO community, which was very positive.
&lt;a href="http://stackalytics.com/report/users/jpena-c"&gt;Javier Peña&lt;/a&gt; is working
on that. &lt;a href="http://stackalytics.com/report/users/dmsimard"&gt;David Simard&lt;/a&gt;
is working on that from the CI part, a lot of stuff. &lt;a href="http://stackalytics.com/report/users/apevec"&gt;Alan
Pevec&lt;/a&gt; is our
guiding light. And &lt;a href="http://stackalytics.com/report/users/mmagr"&gt;Martin
Mágr&lt;/a&gt;,
who is the current PTL - he's stepping down but right now he's the
PTL. A lot of people that are always asking stuff about Packstack and
doing reviews, and actually submitting patches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know, I think that people think that Packstack is dead because
it's not recommended for production use. Only if you really know what
you're doing, you should use it in production, but it's not
recommended. &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/tripleo/"&gt;TripleO&lt;/a&gt; is the recommended stuff for production, and
Packstack is for doing the experiments, and proof-of-concept stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I use it on my home OpenStack deployment, and I do a lot of
experiments. It's pretty good for experimenting, because it's pretty
lightweight, and it's very easy to modify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you very much for your time, and I look forward to what's
coming in Newton!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RDO Mitaka released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/rdo-mitaka-released/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/rdo-mitaka-released/</id>
    <published>2016-04-12T13:47:19+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The RDO community is pleased to announce the general availability of the RDO build for OpenStack Mitaka for RPM-based distributions - CentOS Linux 7 and Red Hat Enterprise Linux. RDO is suitable for building private, public, and hybrid clouds and Mitaka is the 13th release from the &lt;a href="http://openstack.org"&gt;OpenStack project&lt;/a&gt;, which is the work of more than 2500 contributors from around the world. 
(&lt;a href="http://stackalytics.com/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="http://redhatstackblog.redhat.com/2016/03/21/learn-whats-coming-in-openstack-mitaka/"&gt;RedHatStack&lt;/a&gt; for a brief overview of what's new in Mitaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/"&gt;RDO community project&lt;/a&gt; curates, packages, builds, tests, and maintains a complete OpenStack component set for RHEL and CentOS Linux and is a founding member of the &lt;a href="https://wiki.centos.org/SpecialInterestGroup/Cloud"&gt;CentOS Cloud Infrastructure SIG&lt;/a&gt;. The Cloud Infrastructure SIG focuses on delivering a great user experience for CentOS Linux users looking to build and maintain their own on-premise, public or hybrid clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All work on RDO, and on the downstream release, Red Hat OpenStack Platform, is 100% open source, with all code changes going upstream first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a complete list of what's in RDO, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/redhat-openstack/rdoinfo/blob/master/rdo.yml"&gt;the RDO projects yaml file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three ways to get started with RDO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To spin up a proof of concept cloud, quickly, and on limited hardware, try the &lt;a href="http://rdoproject.org/Quickstart"&gt;RDO QuickStart&lt;/a&gt;  You can run RDO on a single node to get a feel for how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a production deployment of RDO, use the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/tripleo/"&gt;TripleO Quickstart&lt;/a&gt; and you'll be running a production cloud in short order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you want to try out OpenStack, but don't have the time or hardware to run it yourself, visit &lt;a href="http://trystack.org/"&gt;TryStack&lt;/a&gt;, where you can use a free public OpenStack instance, running RDO packages, to experiment with the OpenStack management interface and API, launch instances, configure networks, and generally familiarize yourself with OpenStack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting Help&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RDO Project participates in a Q&amp;amp;A service at &lt;a href="http://ask.openstack.org"&gt;ask.openstack.org&lt;/a&gt;, for more developer oriented content we recommend joining the &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/mailman/listinfo/rdo-list"&gt;rdo-list mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. Remember to post a brief introduction about yourself and your RDO story. You can also find extensive documentation on the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/documentation"&gt;RDO docs site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also welcome comments and requests on the &lt;a href="https://lists.centos.org/"&gt;CentOS Mailing lists&lt;/a&gt; and the CentOS IRC Channels (#centos on irc.freenode.net), however we have a more focused audience in the RDO venues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting Involved&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get involved in the OpenStack RPM packaging effort, see the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/community/"&gt;RDO community pages&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://wiki.centos.org/SpecialInterestGroup/Cloud"&gt;CentOS Cloud SIG page&lt;/a&gt;. See also the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/packaging/"&gt;RDO packaging documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us in #rdo on the Freenode IRC network, and follow us at &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/rdocommunity"&gt;@RDOCommunity&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, if you're going to be in Austin for the &lt;a href="http://openstack.org/summit/"&gt;OpenStack Summit&lt;/a&gt; two weeks from now, join us on Thursday at 4:40pm for the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/P6kyWR"&gt;RDO community BoF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RDO Mitaka 3 test day, March 10th, 11th</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/02/rdo-mitaka-3-test-day-march-10th-11th/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/02/rdo-mitaka-3-test-day-march-10th-11th/</id>
    <published>2016-02-23T15:31:05+01:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/testday/mitaka/milestone3/"&gt;Mitaka 3 test day, March 10, 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/testday/mitaka/brno-on-site/"&gt;On-site test day in Brno&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4O8KvC66eeU"&gt;Demo of deploying with TripleO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://releases.openstack.org/mitaka/schedule.html"&gt;Mitaka milestone 3&lt;/a&gt; is scheduled for the week of February 29 - March 4 and, as per usual, we're planning a test day about a week out from that - March 10th and 11th. We've got the usual &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/testday/mitaka/milestone3/"&gt;page of instructions&lt;/a&gt; for testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, however, we have two bonus events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we're delighted that Eliska Malikova is putting together an &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/testday/mitaka/brno-on-site/"&gt;on-site test day at the Red Hat office in Brno&lt;/a&gt;, for anyone in that general area. If you wish to attend, &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/rdo-on-site-test-day-brno-tickets-5934822213"&gt;please register&lt;/a&gt; so that we know how much pizza to order. (Attendance is limited to 50, so please register sooner rather than later.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, as we attempt to get more people testing TripleO (formerly known as RDO Manager), John Trownbridge (that's Trown on IRC) will be doing a demo of the TripleO Quickstart. This will be conducted as a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4O8KvC66eeU"&gt;YouTube live stream&lt;/a&gt; and will also be recorded, and available at that same location after the fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, please, come help us ensure that Mitaka is the best RDO yet. As usual, we'll be on #rdo (on Freenode IRC), and here on rdo-list, to field any questions. Full details are on the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/testday/mitaka/milestone3/"&gt;test day website&lt;/a&gt; and, as usual, we can use lots of help making the test case instructions better, so that more people can participate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Community Meetup at OpenStack Summit, Tokyo</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2015/10/community-meetup-at-openstack-summit-tokyo/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2015/10/community-meetup-at-openstack-summit-tokyo/</id>
    <published>2015-10-14T17:15:07+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We'll be having an &lt;a href="http://sched.co/4MYy"&gt;RDO community meetup&lt;/a&gt; during the upcoming OpenStack Summit in Tokyo. It will be during lunch time (12:45 - 14:00)  in Sakura Lower Level S-1 and S-2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As at previous Summits, we'll be gathering to discuss progress during
the last six months, and plans for the future. Please add discussion items
to the &lt;a href="https://etherpad.openstack.org/p/rdo-tokyo"&gt;agenda&lt;/a&gt; that you'd like for us to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
