<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>RDO</title>
  <subtitle>Tag: Release</subtitle>
  <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/</id>
  <link href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/"/>
  <link href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/tag/release.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-06-08T17:52:06+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name/>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>What did you do in Mitaka? David Moreau Simard</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/05/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-david-moreau-simard/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/05/what-did-you-do-in-mitaka-david-moreau-simard/</id>
    <published>2016-05-06T15:47:48+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing our series "What Did You Do In Mitaka?", I spoke with David Moreau Simard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/zqt2x-5f14b4?from=yiiadmin" data-link="https://www.podbean.com/media/player/zqt2x-5f14b4?from=yiiadmin" height="100" width="100%" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" data-name="pb-iframe-player"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(If the above player doesn't work for you, please download the recording &lt;a href="https://rdocommunity.podbean.com/mf/play/qp7cm4/david-simard.mp3"&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm speaking with &lt;a href="https://github.com/dmsimard"&gt;David Moreau Simard&lt;/a&gt;, who is one of the engineers
who works on &lt;a href="//rdoproject.org"&gt;RDO&lt;/a&gt; at Red Hat. Thanks for taking time to speak with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DMSimard&lt;/strong&gt;: It's a pleasure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: What did you work on in Mitaka?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;: I'm part of the RDO engineering team at Red Hat.
My role is mostly around continuous integration and making sure that
RDO works.
This means that some days I could be implementing new ways of testing
RDO or some other days fixing bugs identified by our CI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as Mitaka is concerned, we got Packstack to a point where it's
able to install and run Tempest against itself.
This is awesome because it's a great way to make sure everything works
properly, sort of a sanity check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This improvement allowed us to make Packstack gate against itself
upstream to prevent regressions from merging by testing each commit.
This was part of a plan to make Packstack part of our testing
pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mitaka, we started using a new project called &lt;a href="https://dmsimard.com/2015/12/07/thinking-outside-the-box-and-outside-the-gate-to-improve-openstack-and-rdo/"&gt;WeIRDO&lt;/a&gt;.
It's meant to use upstream gate integration tests inside our own RDO
testing pipeline.
We really improved our testing coverage in Mitaka with TripleO
quickstart and WeIRDO.
With WeIRDO, we're able to easily test RDO trunk packages against
Packstack and Puppet-OpenStack and the jobs that they provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built a great relationship with projects that consume RDO packages
throughout development cycles.
We mutually benefit from essentially testing each other. So it makes a
lot of sense to stay in touch with these guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I can really tell how the testing coverage for RDO has
improved tremendously, even since liberty.
Mitaka is really the best and most tested release of RDO yet. I want
to extend my thanks to everyone that was involved in making it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: So how about in Newton? What do you think is coming in Newton for
you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;: So, Mitaka was already an awesome cycle from the perspective of
testing coverage that we had for RDO.
We want to keep working on that foundation to increase the coverage
further.
I also want to spend some time on improving monitoring and automation
to make troubleshooting problems easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trunk breaks all the time, and so it takes a lot of time to
troublshoot that, and we want to make that easier. But also have
visibility into the problems that could be coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier I talked about WeIRDO and how we use upstream gate jobs in our
testing pipeline.
In Newton, we want to add Kolla back into our testing pipeline through
WeIRDO.
I had some issues getting Kolla to work reliably in Mitaka but they've
fixed some problems upstream since then so we'll take another look at
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just recently, there's also the Chef OpenStack community – they've been working on
integration testing their cookbooks in the gate.
I'm definitely interested in seeing what they have, and possibly leveraging their work once they're ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other large chunk of work will probably come from our effort in
streamlining and centralizing the different components of RDO.
Right now, we're a bit all over the place… But we've already started
working towards moving to a software factory instance.
Software factory is a project to provide upstream's testing ecosystem
with Git, Zuul, Nodepool, Gerrit and Jenkins.. but in a box, an
appliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will definitely make things easier for everyone since everything
from RDO will be expected to be in this one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: Thank you very much for your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;: I appreciate yours, and it was great working on this great release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;David is dmsimard on &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/dmsimard"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href="https://github.com/dmsimard"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, and on IRC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RDO Mitaka released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/rdo-mitaka-released/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2016/04/rdo-mitaka-released/</id>
    <published>2016-04-12T13:47:19+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The RDO community is pleased to announce the general availability of the RDO build for OpenStack Mitaka for RPM-based distributions - CentOS Linux 7 and Red Hat Enterprise Linux. RDO is suitable for building private, public, and hybrid clouds and Mitaka is the 13th release from the &lt;a href="http://openstack.org"&gt;OpenStack project&lt;/a&gt;, which is the work of more than 2500 contributors from around the world. 
(&lt;a href="http://stackalytics.com/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="http://redhatstackblog.redhat.com/2016/03/21/learn-whats-coming-in-openstack-mitaka/"&gt;RedHatStack&lt;/a&gt; for a brief overview of what's new in Mitaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/"&gt;RDO community project&lt;/a&gt; curates, packages, builds, tests, and maintains a complete OpenStack component set for RHEL and CentOS Linux and is a founding member of the &lt;a href="https://wiki.centos.org/SpecialInterestGroup/Cloud"&gt;CentOS Cloud Infrastructure SIG&lt;/a&gt;. The Cloud Infrastructure SIG focuses on delivering a great user experience for CentOS Linux users looking to build and maintain their own on-premise, public or hybrid clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All work on RDO, and on the downstream release, Red Hat OpenStack Platform, is 100% open source, with all code changes going upstream first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a complete list of what's in RDO, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/redhat-openstack/rdoinfo/blob/master/rdo.yml"&gt;the RDO projects yaml file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three ways to get started with RDO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To spin up a proof of concept cloud, quickly, and on limited hardware, try the &lt;a href="http://rdoproject.org/Quickstart"&gt;RDO QuickStart&lt;/a&gt;  You can run RDO on a single node to get a feel for how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a production deployment of RDO, use the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/tripleo/"&gt;TripleO Quickstart&lt;/a&gt; and you'll be running a production cloud in short order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you want to try out OpenStack, but don't have the time or hardware to run it yourself, visit &lt;a href="http://trystack.org/"&gt;TryStack&lt;/a&gt;, where you can use a free public OpenStack instance, running RDO packages, to experiment with the OpenStack management interface and API, launch instances, configure networks, and generally familiarize yourself with OpenStack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting Help&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RDO Project participates in a Q&amp;amp;A service at &lt;a href="http://ask.openstack.org"&gt;ask.openstack.org&lt;/a&gt;, for more developer oriented content we recommend joining the &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/mailman/listinfo/rdo-list"&gt;rdo-list mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. Remember to post a brief introduction about yourself and your RDO story. You can also find extensive documentation on the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/documentation"&gt;RDO docs site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also welcome comments and requests on the &lt;a href="https://lists.centos.org/"&gt;CentOS Mailing lists&lt;/a&gt; and the CentOS IRC Channels (#centos on irc.freenode.net), however we have a more focused audience in the RDO venues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting Involved&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get involved in the OpenStack RPM packaging effort, see the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/community/"&gt;RDO community pages&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://wiki.centos.org/SpecialInterestGroup/Cloud"&gt;CentOS Cloud SIG page&lt;/a&gt;. See also the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/packaging/"&gt;RDO packaging documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us in #rdo on the Freenode IRC network, and follow us at &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/rdocommunity"&gt;@RDOCommunity&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, if you're going to be in Austin for the &lt;a href="http://openstack.org/summit/"&gt;OpenStack Summit&lt;/a&gt; two weeks from now, join us on Thursday at 4:40pm for the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/P6kyWR"&gt;RDO community BoF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RDO Liberty released in CentOS Cloud SIG</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://rdoproject.org/blog/2015/10/rdo-liberty-released-in-centos-cloud-sig/"/>
    <id>http://rdoproject.org/blog/2015/10/rdo-liberty-released-in-centos-cloud-sig/</id>
    <published>2015-10-22T15:34:54+02:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T17:28:37+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Rich Bowen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the general availability of the RDO build for
OpenStack Liberty for CentOS Linux 7 x86_64, suitable for building
private, public and hybrid clouds. OpenStack Liberty is the 12th release of the open source software collaboratively built by a large number of
contributors around the OpenStack.org project space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/"&gt;RDO community project&lt;/a&gt; curates,
packages, builds, tests and maintains a complete OpenStack component set
for RHEL and CentOS Linux and is a founding member of the &lt;a href="https://wiki.centos.org/SpecialInterestGroup/Cloud"&gt;CentOS Cloud Infrastructure SIG&lt;/a&gt;. The Cloud Infrastructure SIG focus on delivering a great user
experience for CentOS Linux users looking to build and maintain their
own onpremise, public or hybrid clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the comprehensive OpenStack services, libraries and
clients, this release also provides Packstack, a simple installer for
proof-of-concept installations, as small as a single all-in-one box and
&lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/RDO-Manager"&gt;RDO Manager&lt;/a&gt;, an OpenStack
deployment and management tool for production environments based on the
OpenStack TripleO project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="quickstart"&gt;QuickStart:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ensure you have a fully updated CentOS Linux 7/x86_64 machine, and run :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo yum install centos-release-openstack-liberty
sudo yum install openstack-packstack
packstack --allinone
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a more detailed quickstart please refer to the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/QuickStart"&gt;RDO Project hosted
guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For RDO Manager consult the &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/RDO-Manager"&gt;RDO Manager page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RDO project is closely tracking upstream OpenStack projects using the &lt;a href="http://trunk.rdoproject.org/"&gt;Delorean tool&lt;/a&gt; which is producing RPM packages from upstream development
branches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the previous OpenStack Kilo release, RDO is participating
in the Cloud SIG and using CentOS provided infrastructure.
Towards the end of developement cycle packages are imported into &lt;a href="http://wiki.centos.org/HowTos/CommunityBuildSystem"&gt;CentOS Cloud SIG buildsystem&lt;/a&gt; and get eventually published in &lt;a href="http://mirror.centos.org/centos/7/cloud/x86_64/"&gt;Cloud SIG repositories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="getting-help"&gt;Getting Help:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RDO Project provides a Q&amp;amp;A service at ask.openstack.org, for more
developer oriented content we recommend joining the &lt;a href="https://www.redhat.com/mailman/listinfo/rdo-list"&gt;rdo-list mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. Remember to post
a brief introduction about yourself and your RDO story.
You can also find extensive documentation &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/documentation"&gt;on the RDO website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also welcome comments and requests on the &lt;a href="https://lists.centos.org/"&gt;CentOS Mailing lists&lt;/a&gt; and the CentOS IRC Channels ( #centos on
irc.freenode.net ), however we have a more focused audience in the RDO venues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get involved in the OpenStack RPM packaging effort, see &lt;a href="https://www.rdoproject.org/Get_involved"&gt;the "Get Involved" docs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://wiki.centos.org/SpecialInterestGroup/Cloud"&gt;the Cloud SIG docs&lt;/a&gt;  Join us in #rdo on the
Freenode IRC network, and follow us at &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/rdocommunity"&gt;@RDOCommunity on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. And, if you're going to 
be in Tokyo for the OpenStack Summit next week, join us on Wednesday at
lunch for the &lt;a href="http://sched.co/4MYy"&gt;RDO community meetup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd like to thank all RDO developers and CentOS Project for
their effort and support resulting in this release,
especially&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dmsimard - for continuously improving RDO CI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;jpena - for keeping Delorean service up and running&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;jruzicka - for the rdopkg auto-magic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;number80 - for countless reviews and packaging wisdom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;social - for puppet module mastery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;trown - for leading RDO Manager side of the show!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to all the folks who helped with last minute testing in
IRC #rdo channel !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alan Pevec&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud SIG and RDO project member&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
